Marcello Roehrssen

TECH LEADER - TECH ENTHUSIAST

Work experience

> Supermoney.it (2022 - now)

As team leader I introduced several innovations both from a technological point of view (CI/CD, satis, docker, ansible, unit testing) and from a workflow point of view (clear separation between BE and FE, Jira, code review).

#CI/CD, Satis, Docker, Ansible, Testing, Jira, Code review, Automation

Now I'm moving the old monolithic BE into a more modern microservice architecture, with a clear separation of concerns, using rabbitMO and redis as a channel of comunication

#RabbitMQ, Redids, Design patterns, Microservice

> Immobiliare.it (2013 - 2022)

Track record of shipping and maintaining many projects (as backendend dev) over the long term.

#PHP, Symfony, Zend, Doctrine, PHPUnit, Thrift, Ansible, Docker, Composer

As Backend Tech Leader I've done a lot of mentoring and coaching, with pair-programming sessions and in-company workshops

#PHP 7.4/8.3, Testing, Perf test, Design patterns, Problem solving

Developed and maintained various composer plugins, bundles and dev tools that improve development process with extensive documentation

Composer, Symfony bundle, tooling, libraries

Realized a backend stats monitorning System, based on real time metrics and labs metrics. To gather labs metrics I used jmeter (in case of socket-runnig application) or autocannon (in case of http application)

Metrics, Loadtest, Perftest, Jmeter, Autocannon

Wrote a backend framework based on Symfony framework, rewriting the internal kernel andbundles with the objective of making symfony work through socket connections (Thrift) in a way that is easy, fast and efficient replacing an homemade framework improving performance and DX.

#DX, Symfony, Thrift, Refactoring, Efficiency

> Ciao people SRL (2008 - 2013)

As a full stack developer i developed several PHP application (Zend framework, smarty). I've guided company towards AWS for a scala media streaming project (youmedia)

#AWS, Scala, Streaming, Zend framework, smarty

Education

> Master degree in Software Engineer (2006 - 2011)

ABOUT ME

Hello! 👋

I'm Marcello, a developer specialized in backend with 16+ years of experience.

I love the process of improving things, always keeping an eye on both user and dev experience on everything I put my hands on.

I like minimal solutions and I'm highly inspired by projects like Symfony and Doctrine.

PASSIONS & SKILLS

I also like to speriment new programming fields, now i'm learning GOLang, NextJs and **NodeJS**

I also organize some postwork meetups with my collegues, where we experiment thing like Game Development and IoT. Now i'm learning C# and Unity.

I spend most of my learning time improving my softskills, keeping myself up-to date about backend dev and design and reading open source code to get inspiration.



+39 349 43 68 422



marcello.roehrssen@gmail.com



github.com/marcelloroehrssen



linkedin.com/in/marcello1